uleth.ca 2017-11-25

# U of L Web Privacy Statement | University of Lethbridge

The University of Lethbridge is committed to respecting the privacy of all individuals, and operates in accordance with the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act. This document outlines the standards for electronic data collection and use to ensure all members of the University community and public understand and are comfortable with the stewardship of their privacy.

## Email Addresses

Email addresses have been provided by the institution to all faculty and staff to allow them to perform their work and to students for the purpose of enhancing their pursuit of higher education. The University of Lethbridge will only disclose student email addresses in accordance with the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act. Faculties, Schools and Departments maintain the right to use these addresses to contact users for matters of emergency or significant importance to the University community.

The University of Lethbridge may request non-University email addresses only for the purposes that are clearly explained at the time of request. Email addresses will not be used outside of that context and will be kept in strictest confidence.

## Collection, Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

Where personal information is collected and then stored within University of Lethbridge electronic records systems, it will be collected in compliance with the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act and will adhere to the University of Lethbridge Confidentiality of Student Records policy. Personal information collected is used only for the specific purpose it was collected, is disclosed only for the purpose it was collected and is kept only for the length of time required for that specific purpose.

## Web Logs and Cookies

The University of Lethbridge uses Google Analytics to help analyze how the website is used. The tool uses "cookies," which are text files placed on your computer, to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitors' use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity for the University.

The University will not (and will not allow any third party) to use the statistical analytics tool to track or to collect any Personally Identifiable Information (PII) of visitors to our site. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Neither we nor Google will link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of a computer user. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any Personally Identifiable Information from any source, unless you explicitly submit that information via a fill-in form on our website.

## Linking to Other Sites

Where required the University of Lethbridge will link our website to other websites. The University strives to ensure the accuracy of these linkages but the University is not responsible for the content on these external web sites, which may change without notice. The University is not responsible for content deemed offensive or for the privacy policies or statements in effect on outside websites.

## Security of Data

The University of Lethbridge maintains strict data security standards when asking for personal information. When required, credit card information is obtained only for the purpose of a specific transaction and is not stored within University of Lethbridge systems. The University uses industry standard encryption with a signed web certificate to guarantee the safety of data.

## Questions or Comments

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about your privacy, please contact our privacy office.
